OBJECTIVE

Eager to apply knowledge in web development, software development, database management, and software testing to a software development role while also being open to learning new skills.

SUMMARY

Recent college graduate with academic distinction and 6 months of experience in an information technology internship involving modifying and testing stored procedures in Microsoft SQL server, unit testing, regression testing, and code refactoring in .NET, Junit testing in Java applications, and collaborating with others using the Scrum methodology.

EDUCATION

Virginia Military Institute (VMI), Lexington VA Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, May 2024 Concentration: Theory and Application Dean's List (8), Academically Distinguished

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, SQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, (C++ and Linux in progress)

Applications: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL Workbench, Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, Microsoft Office, GitHub, PyCharm, Jira

Other: Agile Development, Scrum, unit testing, regression testing, code refactoring, debugging, REST APIs, Database Design, public speaking

WORK HISTORY

Information Technology Intern, May 2022-August 2022, May 2023-August 2023 Intact Insurance Specialty Solutions, Salem, VA

- Modified and tested stored procedures and SSRS reports in MSSQL
- Added new functionality to existing stored procedures to provide more relevant information to the end user, improving usability and overall customer experience
- Created unit testing project for .NET application
- Wrote up a guide on how to create .NET unit testing project for other developers to reference
- Created test cases for Java application using Junit
- Refactored legacy code in automated .NET application to help the company adhere to clean coding practices such as the DRY principle and Single Responsibility principle
- Demonstrated attention to detail and oral communication by writing up detailed documentation describing the changes made to the code in the .NET application and presenting the changes to the team
- Performed regression testing on automated .NET application to ensure that all functionality was maintained
- Collaborated with an international team using the Scrum methodology
- Used object-oriented programming skills to learn .NET syntax and format

COMPUTER PROJECTS and ACTIVITIES

Senior Capstone Project: The Learning Lab September 2023-May 2024 Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, VA

- Developed a working demo of a gamified learning web application for K-12, including a complete login system with user authentication/authorization and separate user interfaces for teachers and students
- managed project tasks and sprints using Jira
- led a team of two other students by organizing meetings and delegating tasks
- utilized the React.js framework, HTML, and CSS for front-end development
- utilized the Express.js framework to develop REST APIs in Node.js for the back end
- designed and implemented a relational database for the application using LucidChart and phpMyAdmin
- integrated two prototype Unity WebGL games with the React app
- conducted usability testing on the prototype and collected feedback from 10 target users (students and teachers)